<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asian on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/asian/</link><description>Recent content in Asian on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/asian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chicken Satay with Spicy Peanut Sauce</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-satay-with-spicy-peanut-sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-satay-with-spicy-peanut-sauce/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Funky Chicken</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/funky-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/funky-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="sesame-noodles">Sesame Noodles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>1 lb spaghettini (get the thinnest spaghetti you can find)
1⁄2 cup soy sauce
1⁄4 cup sesame oil (some reviewers have said that 1/2 cup of oil is too much and have halved the amount, so use your own)
1⁄3 cup sugar
3 scallions, thinly sliced
1⁄4 cup sesame seeds (or more)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pork and Ginger Pot Stickers</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-ginger-pot-stickers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-ginger-pot-stickers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="pork-and-ginger-filling">Pork and Ginger Filling&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 cups chopped napa cabbage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tablespoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 pound ground pork (Don&amp;rsquo;t get lean pork, the fat is good for juicy and flavorful dumplings)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons minced ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 tablespoons minced garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons thin soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons sesame oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 to 2 cups chicken stock or water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="hot-water-dough">Hot Water Dough&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 to 1 3/4 cups boiling water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="spicy-soy-dipping-sauce">Spicy Soy Dipping Sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/3 cup thin soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup rice wine vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup sliced scallions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon sesame oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon sambal&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Sprinkle cabbage with the 1/2 tablespoon of salt and let stand for 30 minutes. Place the cabbage on a clean dishtowel or cheesecloth and squeeze out any water. The dryer the cabbage the better. In a large bowl thoroughly mix the cabbage with all of the other ingredients, except the chicken stock. Cook a tester to check the seasoning.;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="hot-water-dough-1">Hot Water Dough&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a stainless steel bowl mix flour and salt. Slowly add hot water to flour in 1/4 cup increments. Mix with chopsticks until a ball is formed and the dough is not too hot to handle. On a floured surface, knead dough until it becomes a smooth, elastic ball. Place back in bowl and cover with a damp cloth. Allow to rest for at least 1 hour. Working on a floured surface with floured hands, roll out dough to form a long &amp;rsquo;noodle&amp;rsquo;, 1-inch in diameter. Cut 1/2-inch pieces and turn them over so the cut sides are facing up. Flatten with your palm and roll out thin using a rolling pin. The dumpling wrapper should end up about 3 inches in diameter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="making-the-dumplings">MAKING THE DUMPLINGS:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place a small mound of filling in the middle of the wrapper. (Be very careful not to touch the edges with the filling as this will impede proper sealing of the dumplings. Nothing is worse than dumplings breaking during cooking.) Fold the wrapper in half to form a half moon shape. Starting on one end fold/pinch the wrapper tightly together. Proceed with this fold/pinch method until the dumpling is completely sealed. There will be approximately 10 to 14 folds per dumpling. Rest the dumplings with the folded edges straight up.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="cooking-the-dumplings">COOKING THE DUMPLINGS&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a hot saute pan coated well with oil, place pot stickers flat side down and cook until the bottom is browned. Have pan cover ready and add 1 cup of chicken stock, cover immediately. Be careful, the liquid will splatter! The stock will steam the pot stickers. Check them in 5 minutes as more stock may be needed. The trick here is that once the dumplings are firm and fully cooked the stock will evaporate and the bottoms will crisp-up again.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="spicy-soy-dipping-sauce-1">SPICY SOY DIPPING SAUCE:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine all and serve in a small bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="plating">Plating&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Serve pot stickers on a large platter lined with lettuce with a bowl of dipping sauce on the side.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thai Cucumber Salad</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/thai-cucumber-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/thai-cucumber-salad/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 large cucumbers, peeled, halved lengthwise, seeded, and cut into 1/4-inch slices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup white sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup rice wine vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 jalapeno peppers, seeded and chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup chopped cilantro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup chopped peanuts&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Toss the cucumbers with the salt in a colander, and leave in the sink to drain for 30 minutes. Rinse with cold water, then drain and pat dry with paper towels.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk together the sugar and vinegar in a mixing bowl until the sugar has dissolved. Add the cucumbers, jalapeno peppers, and cilantro; toss to combine. Sprinkle chopped peanuts on top before serving.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>