<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pie on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/pie/</link><description>Recent content in Pie on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/pie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blackberry Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/blackberry-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/blackberry-pie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 pie dough recipe for top and bottom crust&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5-6 cups blackberries, rinsed, picked clean, patted dry (if you use frozen berries, defrost and drain them)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup to 3/4 cup sugar (depending on how sweet your berries are)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon lemon juice (use 2 teaspoons if using store-bought berries)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon lemon zest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 teaspoon almond extract&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 to 6 Tbsp cornstarch, flour, or ground quick cooking instant tapioca (use 4 Tbsp if making the pie with wild-picked berries that include a few not fully ripe berries, 6 Tbsp if making the pie with store-bought very ripe berries)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Toss blackberries with sugar, lemon, cinnamon, almond extract, quick tapioca: Place blackberries, sugar, lemon zest, lemon juice, cinnamon, almond extract, and cornstarch/flour/or ground instant tapioca in a large bowl. Gently fold the berries until they are all well coated with sugar. Let sit for 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll out bottom crust: Preheat oven to 400°F. You should have two balls of pie dough, one for the bottom crust, one for the top crust.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll out one of the balls of pie dough on a lightly floured surface to 12-inch diameter if you are using a 9-inch pie pan, or 13-inch diameter if you are using a 10-inch pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line the bottom of your pie pan with the dough. Chill in refrigerator while you roll out the top crust.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll out top crust: Roll out the second ball of pie dough for the top crust. If you would like to do a lattice top, weave the dough strips as described in How to Make a Lattice Top for a Pie Crust.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spoon berry mixture into pie crust, top with second crust: Spoon the berry mixture into the dough-lined pie dish. For a lattice top, weave strips of pie dough over the top of the fruit-filled pie dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For a solid top, place the second rolled-out pie dough crust on top of the pie. Press ends of strips into the rim of the bottom crust. Use scissors to trim the edges to 1/2-inch from the outer edge of the pie pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fold the edges back over themselves and use your fingers to crimp to seal the edges. If you are using a solid top crust, score the top several times with a sharp knife to create air vents for the steam to escape.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake: Place the pie on the middle rack of the oven. Put a baking sheet on the lower rack to catch any juices that might bubble out of the pie while it&amp;rsquo;s cooking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake the pie in two stages. First bake it at 400°F for 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then place a sheet of aluminum foil over the pie to protect the edges and tops from getting too burnt. (A pie protector is quite useful here.) Reduce the heat to 350°F and bake for an additional 30 minutes, or until the crust has browned and the filling is bubbly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove from oven and place on a wire rack. Cool completely before serving.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Blueberry Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/blueberry-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/blueberry-pie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3/4 cup white sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons cornstarch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cups fresh blueberries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 recipe pastry for a 9 inch double crust pie&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 375 degrees F (190 degrees C).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix sugar, cornstarch, salt, and cinnamon, and sprinkle over blueberries.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line pie dish with one pie crust. Pour berry mixture into the crust, and dot with butter. Cut remaining pastry into 1/2 - 3/4 inch wide strips, and make lattice top. Crimp and flute edges.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake pie on lower shelf of oven for about 50 minutes, or until crust is golden brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Crabapple Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/crabapple-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/crabapple-pie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Favorite Chicken Pot Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/favorite-chicken-pot-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/favorite-chicken-pot-pie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lemon Meringue Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/lemon-meringue-pie-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/lemon-meringue-pie-ii/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lemon Meringue Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/lemon-meringue-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/lemon-meringue-pie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pumpkin Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pumpkin-pie-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pumpkin-pie-ii/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pumpkin Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pumpkin-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pumpkin-pie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 (9 inch) unbaked deep dish pie crust&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 cup white sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon ground ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 teaspoon ground cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 (15 ounce) can LIBBY&amp;rsquo;S(R) 100% Pure Pumpkin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 (12 fluid ounce) can NESTLE(R) CARNATION(R) Evaporated Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 425 degrees F.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine sugar, salt, cinnamon, ginger and cloves in small bowl. Beat eggs lightly in large bowl. Stir in pumpkin and sugar-spice mixture. Gradually stir in evaporated milk. Pour into pie shell.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for 15 minutes. Reduce temperature to 350 degrees F.; bake for 40 to 50 minutes or until knife inserted near center comes out clean. Cool on wire rack for 2 hours. Serve immediately or refrigerate. (Do not freeze as this will cause the crust to separate from the filling.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Rhubarb Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/rhubarb-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/rhubarb-pie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 cups cut rhubarb&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/3 cup sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 tablespoons flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grated peel from one orange&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dash salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>mix sugar, flour, orange peel and salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>combine with rhubarb.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fill a 9&amp;quot; pastry lined pie pan, dot with butter and adjust top crust.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>brush with milk, cut slits.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bake in 400 degree oven or 40 - 50 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Strawberry and/or Rhubarb Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/strawberry-andor-rhubarb-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/strawberry-andor-rhubarb-pie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 cups of 1&amp;quot; slices rhubarb &lt;em>or&lt;/em> 3 cups sliced rhubarb and 1 cup diced strawberries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1-2/3 cup sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 dash salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>preheat oven to 400 deg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>stir, let stand 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pour into pastry&lt;/li>
&lt;li>crumble 2tbsp butter over fruit filling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cut slits &amp;amp; seal edge&lt;/li>
&lt;li>baste with milk for darker crust, if wanted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bake 50 minutes at 400 deg.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Sweet Potato Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/sweet-potato-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/sweet-potato-pie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cups boiled mashed sweet potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg beaten well&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup brown sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>spice to taste (1/4 tsp each)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 450F. Bake for 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Three Berry Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/three-berry-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/three-berry-pie/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="pastry-for-a-double-crust-pie">Pastry for a Double-Crust Pie:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2/3 cup shortening, chilled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 tablespoons cold water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="three-berry-filling">Three-Berry Filling:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup fresh strawberries, halved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cups fresh raspberries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cups fresh blueberries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup white sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons cornstarch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine the flour and salt. Using a pastry blender, cut in the shortening until the pieces are the size of small peas. Sprinkle 1 tablespoon of the water over part of the mixture, then gently toss with a fork. Push moistened portion to the side of the bowl. Repeat, using 1 tablespoon of water at a time, until all is moistened. Divide the dough in half. Form each half into a ball and flatten slightly. Wrap in plastic and refrigerate for at least 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transfer one piece of dough to a lightly floured surface. Roll the dough from the center to the edges to form a 12-inch circle. Wrap the crust around the rolling pin. Unroll it onto a 9-inch pie plate. Ease the crust into the pie plate, being careful not to stretch it. Trim the bottom crust evenly with the rim of the pie plate, and return the pastry-lined pie plate to the refrigerator.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large mixing bowl, stir together the sugar and cornstarch. Add the strawberries, raspberries, and blueberries; gently toss until berries are coated. Allow fruit mixture to stand for about 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat the oven to 375 degrees F (190 degrees C). Place a baking sheet in the oven to preheat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll out the remaining pastry for the top crust. Stir the berry mixture and pour the filling into the pastry-lined pie plate. Place the top crust over the pie and trim the edges, leaving a 1/2-inch overhang. Fold the top crust under the bottom crust, pressing lightly to seal. Crimp the edges of the crust and cut vents in the top to allow steam to escape. To prevent over-browning, cover the edge of the pie with foil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake in the preheated oven on the baking tray for 25 minutes. Remove the foil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for an additional 20 to 30 minutes, or until the filling is bubbling and the crust is golden. Cool on a wire rack.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Chicken Pot Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/ultimate-chicken-pot-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/ultimate-chicken-pot-pie/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>