<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Snack on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/snack/</link><description>Recent content in Snack on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/snack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chipotle Salsa</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chipotle-salsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chipotle-salsa/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d say this makes about 1/2 gallon of salsa &amp;ndash; make sure you have Tupperware. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you could probably freeze extras&amp;hellip; I make the recipe so big because of the size of the cilantro bunch and the size of a typical onion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oatmeal Crackers</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/oatmeal-crackers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/oatmeal-crackers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cups rolled oats&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup flour (wheat preferred)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup toasted wheat germ&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp brown sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp salt, garlic salt, seasoned salt, or celery salt, etc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 tbsp vegetable oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a mixing bowl, stir together oats, flour, wheat germ, brown sugar, and salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make a well in the center and add oil and water all at once.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir till dry ingredients are moistened and form a ball.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divide the ball in half and roll each half onto a greased 8&amp;quot;x12&amp;quot; baking sheet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut dough into 2&amp;quot; squares.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake at 350F for 20-22 minutes or till crisp.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cool on a wire rack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Store in an airtight container.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>* tweaked some proportions using &lt;a href="https://www.allrecipes.com/recipe/214664/oatmeal-crackers/">this recipe&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pretzels</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cups warm water (110-115 degrees F)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons kosher salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 envelope active dry yeast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>22 ounces all-purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 ounces unsalted butter (melted)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vegetable oil (for the bowl and pan)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 cups water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2/3 cup baking soda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large egg yolk (beaten with 1 tablespoon water)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pretzel salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine the 1 1/2 cups warm water, the sugar and kosher salt in the bowl of a stand mixer and sprinkle the yeast on top. Set aside for 5 minutes, or until the mixture foams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the flour and butter and, using the dough hook attachment, mix on low speed until well combined. Change to medium speed and knead until the dough is smooth and pulls away from the side of the bowl, 4 to 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the dough from the bowl, clean the bowl, then oil it well. Return the dough to the bowl, cover with plastic wrap, and set aside in a warm place for 50 to 55 minutes, or until the dough has doubled in size.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat the oven to 450 degrees F. Line 2 half sheet pans with parchment paper and lightly brush with oil. Set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring the 10 cups water and the baking soda to a rolling boil in a 12-inch straight-sided saute pan or a roasting pan (something wide and shallow is best).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, turn the dough out onto a lightly oiled work surface and divide into 8 equal pieces. Roll out each piece of dough into a 24-inch rope. Make a U-shape with the rope, and, holding the ends of the rope, cross them over each other and press onto the bottom of the U in order to form the shape of a pretzel. Place on a half sheet pan. Repeat with the remaining pieces of dough.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One by one, place the pretzels in the boiling water for 30 seconds. Remove them from the water using a large flat spatula. Return them to the sheet pans, brush the top of each pretzel with the beaten egg yolk and water mixture, and sprinkle with pretzel salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake until dark golden brown in color, 12 to 14 minutes. Transfer to a cooling rack for at least 5 minutes before serving.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you don’t have pretzel salt, coarse sea salt will do.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pretzels II</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels-ii/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 package active dry yeast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons packed light brown sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour, plus more for kneading&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 tablespoons unsalted butter, plus more for greasing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon fine salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup baking soda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons coarse salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Warm the milk in a saucepan until it&amp;rsquo;s about 110 degrees; pour into a medium bowl and sprinkle in the yeast. Let the yeast soften, about 2 minutes; stir in the brown sugar and 1 cup flour with a wooden spoon. Dice 2 tablespoons butter and soften; stir into the mix. Add the remaining 1 1/4 cups flour and the fine salt to make a sticky dough. Turn the dough out onto a lightly floured surface and knead, adding more flour if needed, until smooth but still slightly tacky, about 5 minutes. Shape into a ball, place in a lightly greased bowl and cover with plastic wrap. Let rise in a warm spot until doubled in size, about 1 hour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat the oven to 450 degrees and grease a large baking sheet. Punch the dough to deflate it, then turn out onto a lightly floured surface. (If the dough seems tight, cover and let rest until it relaxes.) Divide the dough into 6 pieces. Roll and stretch each piece with the palms of your hands into a 30-inch rope, holding the ends and slapping the middle of the rope on the counter as you stretch. Form each rope into a pretzel shape.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dissolve the baking soda in 3 cups warm water in a shallow baking dish. Gently dip each pretzel in the soda solution, then arrange on the prepared baking sheet and sprinkle with the coarse salt. Bake until golden, 10 to 12 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>