<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Snack on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/snack/</link><description>Recent content in Snack on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/snack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chipotle Salsa</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chipotle-salsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chipotle-salsa/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d say this makes about 1/2 gallon of salsa &amp;ndash; make sure you have Tupperware.</description></item><item><title>Oatmeal Crackers</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/oatmeal-crackers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/oatmeal-crackers/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 cups rolled oats 1 cup flour (wheat preferred) 1/3 cup toasted wheat germ 1 Tbsp brown sugar 1/2 tsp salt, garlic salt, seasoned salt, or celery salt, etc 1/2 cup water 5 tbsp vegetable oil Directions In a mixing bowl, stir together oats, flour, wheat germ, brown sugar, and salt.</description></item><item><title>Pretzels</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 cups warm water (110-115 degrees F) 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoons kosher salt 1 envelope active dry yeast 22 ounces all-purpose flour 2 ounces unsalted butter (melted) Vegetable oil (for the bowl and pan) 10 cups water 2/3 cup baking soda 1 large egg yolk (beaten with 1 tablespoon water) Pretzel salt Directions Combine the 1 1/2 cups warm water, the sugar and kosher salt in the bowl of a stand mixer and sprinkle the yeast on top.</description></item><item><title>Pretzels II</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pretzels-ii/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup milk 1 package active dry yeast 3 tablespoons packed light brown sugar 2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour, plus more for kneading 10 tablespoons unsalted butter, plus more for greasing 1 teaspoon fine salt 1/3 cup baking soda 2 tablespoons coarse salt Directions Warm the milk in a saucepan until it&amp;rsquo;s about 110 degrees; pour into a medium bowl and sprinkle in the yeast.</description></item></channel></rss>