<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work Blog on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/</link><description>Recent content in Work Blog on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Incredible Feats of Productivity</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-05-22-incredible-feats-of-productivity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-05-22-incredible-feats-of-productivity/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don’t know if it’s the ever-increasing volume of bad news I’m getting from my tech podcasts, the impending AI apocalypse, or perhaps myself atrophying a bit and sticking with what I know, but if I hadn’t already switched to Linux, the news that operating systems were baking in surveillance &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> certainly would have accelerated my shift. So I thought I’d discuss how I switched to Linux and why, but start with the tools I use to get things done in Linux, such as tools for writing, and how I de-linked myself from any one productivity suite.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Brief Intro to Symbolic Expressions in Python</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-05-21-sympy-expressions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-05-21-sympy-expressions/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you like keeping all your computing in one language (and that language is Python), but want some of the equation manipulation capabilities of Mathematica, have you tried Sympy?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Techniques for solving four-bar linkage equations</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-03-13-sympy-fourbar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-03-13-sympy-fourbar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The purpose of this tutorial is to show you the power of sympy for analyzing the math of linkages and kinematics. We will walk through a full example of solving for the motion of a four-bar linkage, with a variety of approaches explored along the way with an eye towards addressing sympy&amp;rsquo;s limitations, compared to other symbolic math environments like Mathematica, Maple, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inverse Dynamics in Mujoco</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-03-11-double-pendulum-inverse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-03-11-double-pendulum-inverse/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This tutorial shows you how to use MuJoCo to compute the required torques to achieve a given directory. The example compares the computed torque from two different integrators.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Python and Jupyter in Containers</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-02-29-docker-python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-02-29-docker-python/</guid><description>&lt;p>Python for me has always been easy to learn, but hard to get working. There are a number of ways to install and manage packages &amp;ndash; pip, anaconda, virtual environments, poetry &amp;ndash; unfortunately, each code project has spent different amounts of effort tuning their install approach to suit one, maybe two of these paradigms. This means that the success of installing a complex python codebase depends heavily on the approach you took to install it, and it may or may not work. Anaconda, for example, which has been my tried-and-true approach to a uniform package management experience across operating systems for many years, has itself fallen victim to the increasing complexity of managing dependencies, or &amp;ldquo;dependency hell&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using ROS2 over VPNs in the Classroom</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-01-25-ros2-over-vpn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-01-25-ros2-over-vpn/</guid><description>The purpose of this tutorial is to provide a way to provide access to ROS2 style data collection between computers, when specific kinds of access to the users&amp;rsquo; network is restricted.</description></item><item><title>Wrapping up "Flexible Robotics"</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-01-04-class-wrapup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2024-01-04-class-wrapup/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had the pleasure of teaching a new class called &amp;ldquo;Flexible Robotics&amp;rdquo; while on sabbatical at Bilkent University in Ankara, Turkey this Fall. The class was a 13 person, senior-level elective course that covered some of the same concepts as my graduate-level &amp;ldquo;Foldable Robotics&amp;rdquo; class that I have taught at ASU since 2016, but introduced about 75% new material, based on the needs of undergraduates in their senior year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Micro Servo Data Collection, Parameter Identification, and Modeling: Parts 5 and 6</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-12-07-servo-fitting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-12-07-servo-fitting/</guid><description>&lt;video controls width="100%" loop autoplay muted src="servo-fitting.mp4">
This browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the last article I took some data from a small, off-the-shelf servo, the SG90, 9 gram micro-servo. In this article, I continue with modeling and parameter fitting. This work was done to prepare for the class I developed, called &lt;em>Flexible Robotics&lt;/em>. This is an undergraduate course with a focus on mechanism design and kinematics, experimentation, prototyping, parameter ID and design optimization. I introduced the python interface to MuJoCo as our tool of choice for modeling and simulation in the second half of the course, as it is both relativly easy to pick up and it motivates many interesting discussions about contact, compliance, and modeling decisions. So this article focuses on how to model the servo using MuJoCo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Micro Servo Data Collection, Parameter Identification, and Modeling: Parts 1-4</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-12-01-servo-modeling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-12-01-servo-modeling/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Finding good information on low-cost servos is difficult. In the next articles, I will describe my informal journey finding and identifying the motor parameters for a SG90 9-gram servo motor. These motors are ubiquitous at the low end of robotics parts, and are thus quite attractive for making affordable robots in the classroom. The quality of these motors varies widely, however, and little information has been collected on them in one place. Different manufacturers often give only some specifications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adjusting Gait Timing with an ESP32-based Web Framework in MicroPython</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-11-07-gaits-with-microdot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-11-07-gaits-with-microdot/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been working on this for a while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simulating Spherical Mechanisms in MuJoCo</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-10-25-spherical_four_bar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-10-25-spherical_four_bar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The purpose of this example is to show how easy it is to create spherical mechanisms in MuJoCo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two new videos</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-10-13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-10-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have created two new tutorial videos for modeling complex 3D kinematics in CAD. One video covers Solidworks, and the other covers Autodesk Fusion 360. Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quaternion Tutorials</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-10-06/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-10-06/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am adding a &lt;a href="https://flexible-robotics.github.io/tutorials/kinematics/06-quaternions/">module on quaternions&lt;/a> to my flexible robotics class, and am pretty happy with the way it is turning out. Please check it out!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Demonstrating Unicast in ROS2 with CycloneDDS</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-09-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-09-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>This has been converted to a tutorial and moved &lt;a href="https://www.danaukes.com/notebook/ros2/configuring-unicast-dds-with-cyclone/">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flexible Robotics, Mujoco, and Visas</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-09-08/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-09-08/</guid><description>&lt;p>I arrived at Bilkent University this week, and immediately jumped in to course creation with Onur Ozcan. We filed the paperwork to create &lt;em>Flexible Robotics&lt;/em>, a new course in the Bilkent Mechanical Engineering Department that will be thematically linked to my foldable robotics course back at ASU, with a few potential changes:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mujoco Updates</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-27/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-27/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning MuJoCo and have some informal things to share about what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far^[I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the python interface in this article.]:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updates on MuJoCo</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>Installing mujoco on linux with anaconda is not well documented. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten an install to work, and finally without many of the hacks recommended around the web. See my &lt;a href="https://danaukes.com/notebook/mujoco-notes/">mujoco notes&lt;/a> for my current, up-to-date installation and usage notes and links.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microdot Updates</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m slowly trying to merge some existing servo code with a micro web framework called microdot in order to be able to encode &amp;ldquo;gait&amp;rdquo; parameters from a webpage on an ESP32.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Servo Comparison</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-08-servo-comparison/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-08-servo-comparison/</guid><description>&lt;!-- One of the issues with low cost RC servos is their vastly different characteristics. -->
&lt;p>When I&amp;rsquo;m developing a course or camp, I often don&amp;rsquo;t have time to do in-depth research on parts or to pre-order multiple rounds of test parts in order to properly research what I need. But RC servo motors &amp;ndash; to a robotics professor like me &amp;ndash; are one of the cornerstones to teaching half of the sensing &amp;amp; actuation loop so often required of a robotic or embedded system. If the servo doesn&amp;rsquo;t work right, the class stalls out and the students get frustrated! So, over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized I have to find a solution to the following question&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-07-first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/work-blog/2023-08-07-first-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>The idea of this section of my website is to document some of my daily work during my sabbatical year and hopefully onward. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s hard to organize my thoughts and plan out my work, so hopefully writing down my thoughts in a weekly series will help me organize my thoughts better and document my progress through it all.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>