<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>casserole on Dan Aukes</title>
    <link>http://danaukes.com/tags/casserole/</link>
    <description>Recent content in casserole on Dan Aukes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://danaukes.com/tags/casserole/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Ever Green Bean Casserole</title>
      <link>http://danaukes.com/recipes/best-ever-green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danaukes.com/recipes/best-ever-green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Topping  2 medium onions, thinly sliced 1/4 cup all-purpose flour 2 tablespoons panko bread crumbs 1 teaspoon kosher salt Nonstick cooking spray  Beans and Sauce  2 tablespoons plus 1 teaspoon kosher salt, divided 1 pound fresh green beans, rinsed, trimmed and halved 2 tablespoons unsalted butter 12 ounces mushrooms, trimmed and cut into 1/2-inch pieces 1/2 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/4 teaspoon freshly ground nutmeg 2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1 cup chicken broth 1 cup half-and-half  Directions  Preheat the oven to 475 degrees F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Casserole</title>
      <link>http://danaukes.com/recipes/breakfast-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danaukes.com/recipes/breakfast-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  12 eggs 1/2 cup flour 1 teaspoon baking powder 2 cups cottage cheese (less than one large container) 2 cups grated Cheddar cheese 2 cups grated Monterey Jack cheese 1/4 cup melted butter 1/2 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili Con Cornbread</title>
      <link>http://danaukes.com/recipes/chili-con-cornbread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danaukes.com/recipes/chili-con-cornbread/</guid>
      <description>Cornbread Ingredients  Cooking spray to grease pan 1/4 cup butter or margarine (1/2 stick) 1 cup milk 1 large egg 1 1/4 cups yellow, white or blue cornmeal 1 cup all-purpose flour 1 tablespoon granulated sugar 1 tablespoon baking powder 1/2 teaspoon salt  optional  1 can sweet corn cheese for topping  Chili Ingredients  1 lb ground beef 1 can dark red kidney beans 1 can black beans 1 onion a couple cloves garlic 1 can diced tomatoes 1 can tomato paste or sauce chili powder to taste  Directions Cornbread Prep  Heat the oven to 400°F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Bean Artichoke Casserole</title>
      <link>http://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-artichoke-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-artichoke-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 (15.5 ounce) cans French cut green beans, drained 2 (14 ounce) cans artichoke hearts, drained 2 cups Italian seasoned bread crumbs 8 ounces grated Parmesan cheese 8 ounces shredded mozzarella cheese 2 tablespoons garlic powder salt and pepper to taste 1/2 cup olive oil  Directions  Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Bean Casserole</title>
      <link>http://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tablespoons butter 2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon white sugar 1/4 cup onion, diced 1 cup sour cream 3 (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grilled Marinated Flank Steak</title>
      <link>http://danaukes.com/recipes/grilled-marinated-flank-steak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danaukes.com/recipes/grilled-marinated-flank-steak/</guid>
      <description>Images </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
