<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>side on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipe_tags/side/</link><description>Recent content in side on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://danaukes.com/recipe_tags/side/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'Simple is Best' Dressing</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/simple-is-best-dressing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/simple-is-best-dressing/</guid><description>Ingredients 3/4 cup (1 1/2 sticks) unsalted butter plus more for baking dish 1 pound good-quality day-old white bread, torn into 1&amp;quot; pieces (about 10 cups) 2 1/2 cups chopped yellow onions 1 1/2 cups 1/4&amp;quot; slices celery 1/2 cup chopped flat-leaf parsley 2 tablespoons chopped fresh sage 1 tablespoon chopped fresh rosemary 1 tablespoon chopped fresh thyme 2 teaspoons kosher salt 1 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper 2 1/2 cups low-sodium chicken broth, divided 2 large eggs Directions Preheat oven to 250°F.</description></item><item><title>Acorn Squash with Apple</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/acorn-squash-with-apple/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/acorn-squash-with-apple/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 acorn squash 2 apples, cored and sliced 1 tablespoon butter 2 tablespoons brown sugar 1 tablespoon finely chopped walnuts 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon Directions To easily peel the acorn squash without losing a lot of vegetable, gently drop the squash in a large pot of boiling water, and boil for 15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Balsamic Roasted Beet Salad</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/balsamic-roasted-beet-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/balsamic-roasted-beet-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients 8 medium-size beets, tops removed and scrubbed 1/2 cup balsamic vinegar 1/2 cup good olive oil 2 teaspoons Dijon mustard, such as Grey Poupon Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 4 ounces baby arugula 1/3 cup roasted, salted Marcona almonds, toasted 4 ounces soft goat cheese, such as Montrachet, crumbled Directions Preheat the oven to 400 degrees.</description></item><item><title>Best Ever Green Bean Casserole</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/best-ever-green-bean-casserole/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/best-ever-green-bean-casserole/</guid><description>Ingredients Topping 2 medium onions, thinly sliced 1/4 cup all-purpose flour 2 tablespoons panko bread crumbs 1 teaspoon kosher salt Nonstick cooking spray Beans and Sauce 2 tablespoons plus 1 teaspoon kosher salt, divided 1 pound fresh green beans, rinsed, trimmed and halved 2 tablespoons unsalted butter 12 ounces mushrooms, trimmed and cut into 1/2-inch pieces 1/2 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/4 teaspoon freshly ground nutmeg 2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1 cup chicken broth 1 cup half-and-half Directions Preheat the oven to 475 degrees F.</description></item><item><title>Butterflake Rolls</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/butterflake-rolls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/butterflake-rolls/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chicken Satay with Spicy Peanut Sauce</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-satay-with-spicy-peanut-sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-satay-with-spicy-peanut-sauce/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chipotle Salsa</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/chipotle-salsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/chipotle-salsa/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d say this makes about 1/2 gallon of salsa &amp;ndash; make sure you have Tupperware.</description></item><item><title>Corn with Winter Squash and Spinach and Basil</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/corn-with-winter-squash-and-spinach-and-basil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/corn-with-winter-squash-and-spinach-and-basil/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Czech Cabbage Rolls</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/czech-cabbage-rolls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/czech-cabbage-rolls/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb sausage 1 lb lean ground beef 1 large diced onion 3 small cans saurkraut 1 large head of cabbage 1/2 c long grain rice, uncooked 1/2 c broth (any kind or water) 4 clove diced garlic (to taste) salt &amp;amp; pepper to taste 1 Tbsp allspice, ground (my own personal addition) Directions Core head of cabbage and put in a stock pot with water (core side down) and steam.</description></item><item><title>Czech Potato Dumplings</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/czech-potato-dumplings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/czech-potato-dumplings/</guid><description>Ingredients Mashed potatoes Egg Salt All purpose flour Directions I had some leftover mashed potatoes from last night&amp;rsquo;s dinner and there&amp;rsquo;s no better way to use them than making potato dumplings!</description></item><item><title>Greek Potatoes</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/greek-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/greek-potatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients 8 large potatoes, peeled, cut into large wedges (about 6-7 wedges per potato) 4 garlic cloves, minced (more garlic is a good thing, less garlic is a no-no for this recipe) 1/2 cup olive oil 1 cup water 1 tablespoon dried oregano (to taste) 1 large lemon, juiced sea salt fresh coarse ground black pepper Directions Preheat oven to 420°F A reviewer has suggested spraying the baking pan with Pam - that sounds like a great idea!</description></item><item><title>Green Bean Artichoke Casserole</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-artichoke-casserole/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-artichoke-casserole/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 (15.5 ounce) cans French cut green beans, drained 2 (14 ounce) cans artichoke hearts, drained 2 cups Italian seasoned bread crumbs 8 ounces grated Parmesan cheese 8 ounces shredded mozzarella cheese 2 tablespoons garlic powder salt and pepper to taste 1/2 cup olive oil Directions Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C).</description></item><item><title>Green Bean Casserole</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons butter 2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon white sugar 1/4 cup onion, diced 1 cup sour cream 3 (14.</description></item><item><title>Homesteader Cornbread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/homesteader-cornbread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/homesteader-cornbread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 cups cornmeal 2 1/2 cups milk 2 cups all-purpose flour 1 tablespoon baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 2/3 cup white sugar 2 eggs 1/2 cup vegetable oil Directions Preheat oven to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C).</description></item><item><title>Indian Spiced Sweet Potatoes</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/indian-spiced-sweet-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/indian-spiced-sweet-potatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 pounds sweet potatoes or yams Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 3 tablespoons clarified butter or ghee 1/2 teaspoon coriander seeds 1/2 teaspoon cumin seeds 1/2 teaspoon brown or black mustard seeds 1/2 teaspoon turmeric 4 fresh curry leaves, optional 2 tablespoons chopped fresh cilantro Juice of 1/2 lime Directions Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F.</description></item><item><title>Kale Soup With Potatoes and Sausage</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/kale-soup-with-potatoes-and-sausage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/kale-soup-with-potatoes-and-sausage/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound linguiça or uncured Spanish chorizo, cut across into 1/8-inch-thick slices 1 large onion, peeled and chopped 1 clove garlic, peeled and minced 2 large baking potatoes, peeled and cut into 1/4-inch cubes 1 ½ heads kale, stemmed and coarsely chopped (about 6 cups) 4 cups chicken broth, homemade or low-sodium canned 1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar 2 teaspoons kosher salt Freshly ground pepper to taste 3 plum tomatoes, cored and cut into 1/2-inch dice Directions Place the sausage in a large pot over medium-low heat and cook until it begins to render its fat, about 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>One Pot Chicken and Dirty Rice</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-and-dirty-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-and-dirty-rice/</guid><description>Ingredients Marinade 1 tsp salt 1 tsp garlic powder 1 1/2 tsp paprika 1/2 tsp pepper 1/2 tsp dried minced onion 1/2 tsp cayenne pepper 1/2 tsp oregano 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes 1 tsp lemon juice Tbsp enough olive oil to make a paste about 1 Rest of Dish 2 Tbsp Olive oil 1 link of andouille sausage sliced into 1/4&amp;quot; slices 4 bone-in skin on chicken thighs 1 medium yellow onion diced 1 jalapeno pepper seeded and diced 2 celery stalks diced 1/4 tsp cayenne pepper pinch of red pepper flakes salt and pepper to taste 1 cup DRY long-grain rice 2 1/4 cup chicken stock or broth Sliced green onions for garnish Minced fresh parsley for garnish Directions Combine all marinade ingredients in a medium sized mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>One Pot Chicken and Dirty Rice</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-and-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-and-rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 cups uncooked basmati rice 6 chicken thighs 1 1/2 teaspoon mixed herbs 2 teaspoon smoked paprika 1 teaspoon onion powder 1 teaspoon garlic powder 2 tablespoon Olive oil 1 cup onion chopped any types of onion would work for this recipe.</description></item><item><title>One Pot Chicken, Mushroom and Rainbow Chard Pasta</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-mushroom-and-rainbow-chard-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-mushroom-and-rainbow-chard-pasta/</guid><description>Ingredients ¼ cup extra virgin olive oil 1 lb boneless, skinless chicken breasts, cut into small cubes 10 ounces baby bella mushrooms, sliced 1 large bunch of Rainbow chard (or traditional Swiss Chard), removed from stems and torn 1 large shallot, diced 4 cloves of garlic, minced 8 ounces Orecchiette pasta (or pasta of choice) 3½ cups reduced sodium chicken broth ¼ cup freshly grated Parmesan cheese Sea salt and fresh ground pepper to taste Directions In a large pot, heat olive oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Parmesean Salad</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/parmesean-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/parmesean-salad/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pork and Ginger Pot Stickers</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-ginger-pot-stickers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-ginger-pot-stickers/</guid><description>Ingredients Pork and Ginger Filling 2 cups chopped napa cabbage 1/2 tablespoon salt 1/2 pound ground pork (Don&amp;rsquo;t get lean pork, the fat is good for juicy and flavorful dumplings) 2 tablespoons minced ginger 1 1/2 tablespoons minced garlic 2 tablespoons thin soy sauce 3 tablespoons sesame oil 1 egg 1 to 2 cups chicken stock or water Hot Water Dough 4 cups all-purpose flour 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 1/2 to 1 3/4 cups boiling water Spicy Soy Dipping Sauce 1/3 cup thin soy sauce 1/3 cup rice wine vinegar 1/3 cup sliced scallions 1 teaspoon sesame oil 1 tablespoon sambal Directions Sprinkle cabbage with the 1/2 tablespoon of salt and let stand for 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Potato Galette</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/potato-galette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/potato-galette/</guid><description>INGREDIENTS 2½ pounds (5 to 6 large) Yukon Gold potatoes, scrubbed and sliced 1/8 inch thick (see note) 5 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted 1 tablespoon cornstarch 1 teaspoon table salt ½ teaspoon ground black pepper 1½ teaspoons chopped fresh rosemary leaves (optional) NOTE In order for the potato cake to hold together, it is important to slice the potatoes no more than 1/8 inch (3 mm) thick and to make sure the slices are thoroughly dried before assembling the cake.</description></item><item><title>potato salad</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/potato-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/potato-salad/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Red and Sweet Potato Salad</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/red-and-sweet-potato-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/red-and-sweet-potato-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients 6 red potatoes, diced 3 large sweet potatoes, diced 3/4 cup mayonnaise 1/2 red onion, diced 1 tablespoon prepared horseradish 1 tablespoon spicy brown mustard 1 tablespoon roasted garlic-flavored olive oil 1/4 pound crumbled cooked bacon 1 pinch garlic powder 1 pinch sea salt 1 pinch ground white pepper 1 pinch paprika Directions Place red potatoes and sweet potatoes into a large pot and cover with salted water; bring to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Samosas</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/samosas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/samosas/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Saurkraut</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/saurkraut/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/saurkraut/</guid><description>Ingredients 5 pounds green cabbage, shredded 3 tablespoons pickling salt 1 tablespoon juniper berries 2 teaspoons caraway seeds 1 quart water, in a sanitized glass jar Directions In large mixing bowl, mix cabbage thoroughly with salt, juniper berries, and caraway seeds, using hands or tongs.</description></item><item><title>Sicilian Cauliflower and Black Olive Gratin</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/sicilian-cauliflower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/sicilian-cauliflower/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 generous head green or white cauliflower (2 to 2 1/2 pounds) Salt 1 small onion, finely chopped 3 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil 2 garlic cloves, minced 16 imported oil-cured black olives, pitted and cut in half 2 tablespoons minced fresh parsley Freshly ground pepper ½ cup freshly grated Pecorino or Parmesan, or a combination Directions Break up the cauliflower into small florets while you bring a large pot of water to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Split Pea Soup</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/split-pea-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/split-pea-soup/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 1/4 cups dried split peas 2 quarts cold water 1 1/2 pounds ham bone 2 onions, thinly sliced 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon ground black pepper 1 pinch dried marjoram 3 stalks celery, chopped 3 carrots, chopped 1 potato, diced Directions In a large stock pot, cover peas with 2 quarts cold water and soak overnight.</description></item><item><title>Squash Pickles</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/squash-pickles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/squash-pickles/</guid><description>Ingredients ¼ cup salt 2 ½ pounds young yellow squash and zucchini, sliced into rounds 1 green bell pepper, seeded and sliced into strips 2 small onions, thinly sliced 2 ¼ cups white sugar 2 cups distilled white vinegar 2 teaspoons mustard seed 1 teaspoon ground turmeric 1 teaspoon celery seed Directions In a large non-aluminum pot, combine the squash, bell pepper, and onions.</description></item><item><title>Tabbouleh</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/tabbouleh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/tabbouleh/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup bulgur 1 2/3 cups boiling water 1/3 cup olive oil 1/3 cup lemon juice 1 cup chopped green onions 1 cup chopped fresh parsley 1/4 cup chopped fresh mint 3 tomatoes, chopped 1 cucumber - peeled, seeded and chopped 1 teaspoon salt ground black pepper to taste Directions Combine bulgur and boiling water in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Thai Cucumber Salad</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/thai-cucumber-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/thai-cucumber-salad/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 large cucumbers, peeled, halved lengthwise, seeded, and cut into 1/4-inch slices 1 tablespoon salt 1/2 cup white sugar 1/2 cup rice wine vinegar 2 jalapeno peppers, seeded and chopped 1/4 cup chopped cilantro 1/2 cup chopped peanuts Directions Toss the cucumbers with the salt in a colander, and leave in the sink to drain for 30 minutes.</description></item></channel></rss>