<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bread on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipe_tags/bread/</link><description>Recent content in bread on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://danaukes.com/recipe_tags/bread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Banana Banana Bread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/banana-banana-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/banana-banana-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cups all-purpose flour 1 teaspoon baking soda 1/4 teaspoon salt 1/2 cup butter 3/4 cup brown sugar 2 eggs, beaten 2 1/3 cups mashed overripe bananas Directions Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C).</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/banana-bread-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/banana-bread-ii/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 to 3 very ripe bananas, peeled (about 1 1/4 to 1 1/2 cups mashed) 1/3 cup melted butter, unsalted or salted 1 teaspoon baking soda Pinch of salt 3/4 cup sugar (1/2 cup if you would like it less sweet, 1 cup if more sweet) 1 large egg, beaten 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 1 1/2 cups of all-purpose flour Directions Preheat the oven to 350°F (175°C), and butter a 4x8-inch loaf pan.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/banana-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/banana-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 cup butter 1 cup sugar 2 eggs 3 bananas(mashed up) 2 cup flour 1 tsp baking soda 1/2 tsp salt Directions mash butter and sugar together add eggs and mashed bananas to mix combine dry ingredients mix wet and dry together and stir bake at 375 deg.</description></item><item><title>Best Bread Machine Bread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/best-bread-machine-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/best-bread-machine-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup warm water (110 degrees F45 degrees C) 2 tablespoons white sugar 1 (.</description></item><item><title>Butterflake Rolls</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/butterflake-rolls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/butterflake-rolls/</guid><description/></item><item><title>French Bread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/french-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/french-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cups warm water 1 tablespoon yeast 1 tablespoon vegetable oil 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoons salt 5 to 5 1/2 cups bread flour Directions Dissolve yeast in warm water (110 degrees) and sugar in large bowl; allow yeast to proof or foam (about 10 minutes).</description></item><item><title>Grandmother's Buttermilk Cornbread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/grandmothers-buttermilk-cornbread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/grandmothers-buttermilk-cornbread/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homesteader Cornbread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/homesteader-cornbread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/homesteader-cornbread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 cups cornmeal 2 1/2 cups milk 2 cups all-purpose flour 1 tablespoon baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 2/3 cup white sugar 2 eggs 1/2 cup vegetable oil Directions Preheat oven to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C).</description></item><item><title>No Knead English Muffins</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/no-knead-english-muffins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/no-knead-english-muffins/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cups (285 grams) bread flour 1 cup (142 grams) whole-wheat flour 2 3/4 teaspoons kosher salt, preferably Diamond Crystal (may substitute half as much table salt by volume) 1 1/4 teaspoons instant yeast (not rapid-rise) 1 1/2 cups (355 milliliters) cold milk (any percentage) 1/4 cup (100 grams) honey 1 large egg white, cold 1 cup (142 grams) fine cornmeal, for dusting 2 tablespoons (30 grams) unsalted butter, bacon fat or oil, plus more as needed Directions In a large bowl, whisk together the bread flour, whole wheat flour, kosher salt and yeast until well combined.</description></item><item><title>Pizza Crust</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/pizza-crust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/pizza-crust/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 cups Flour 2 cups Water 2 rounded tsp / 1 packet yeast 1/2 tsp salt 1 tbsp sugar Directions Heat one cup of water to 110-120 deg F (usually ~30 seconds in the microwave) Add sugar and yeast; stir and set aside for 10 minutes to proof Mix flour and salt in a big metal bowl After ten minutes, if the yeast has become frothy, add it and one more cup water to the flour mixture Stir with a mixer for ~10 minutes.</description></item><item><title>White Bread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/white-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/white-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 1.5 Pound Loaf 1 cup and two tablespoons hot water (115-125 deg F) 2 tablespoons oil 2 tablespoons sugar 1 teaspoon salt 3 cups bread flour 5 teaspoons red star quick rise yeast 2 Pound Loaf 1 1/2 cups hot water (115-125 deg F) 3 tablespoons oil 3 tablespoons sugar 1 1/2 teaspoon salt 4 cups bread flour 2 tablespoons red star quick rise yeast Important: Carefully measure the hot water and make sure it&amp;rsquo;s between 115-125 deg F by using a cooking thermometer Measure and add liquid ingredients to the bread pan Measure and add dry ingredients (except yeast) to the bread pan Use your finger to form a well (hole) in the flour where you will pour the yeast.</description></item><item><title>Zucchini Bread</title><link>https://danaukes.com/recipes/zucchihi-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danaukes.com/recipes/zucchihi-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients Butter and flour for preparing baking pans 3 cups all-purpose flour 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon baking soda 1 teaspoon baking powder 4 teaspoons ground cinnamon 3½ cups grated zucchini (you can use as few as 2 cups and as much as 4 cups) 3 eggs ½ cup apple sauce ½ cup vegetable oil 2¼ cups granulated sugar 4 teaspoons vanilla extract 1 cup chopped pecans Directions Preheat oven to 350 degrees F.</description></item></channel></rss>