<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meat on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/meat/</link><description>Recent content in Meat on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/meat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kale Soup With Potatoes and Sausage</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/kale-soup-with-potatoes-and-sausage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/kale-soup-with-potatoes-and-sausage/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound linguiça or uncured Spanish chorizo, cut across into 1/8-inch-thick slices 1 large onion, peeled and chopped 1 clove garlic, peeled and minced 2 large baking potatoes, peeled and cut into 1/4-inch cubes 1 ½ heads kale, stemmed and coarsely chopped (about 6 cups) 4 cups chicken broth, homemade or low-sodium canned 1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar 2 teaspoons kosher salt Freshly ground pepper to taste 3 plum tomatoes, cored and cut into 1/2-inch dice Directions Place the sausage in a large pot over medium-low heat and cook until it begins to render its fat, about 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Moroccan Slow-Cooked Lamb</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/moroccan-slow-cooked-lamb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/moroccan-slow-cooked-lamb/</guid><description>Makes 6 servings
Ingredients 1 tablespoon ground cumin 2 teaspoons ground coriander 1 1/2 teaspoons salt 1 teaspoon fennel seeds 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper 2 1/2 pounds trimmed boned lamb shoulder, cut into 1 1/2- to 2-inch pieces 4 tablespoons olive oil, divided 1 large onion, finely chopped 1 tablespoon tomato paste 2 cups low-salt chicken broth 1 15 1/2-ounce can garbanzo beans (chickpeas), drained 1 cup dried apricots (about 5 ounces) 2 large plum tomatoes, chopped 2 cinnamon sticks 1 tablespoon minced peeled fresh ginger 2 teaspoons (packed) grated lemon peel 2 tablespoons chopped fresh cilantro Directions Mix first 6 ingredients in large bowl.</description></item></channel></rss>