<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pork on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/pork/</link><description>Recent content in Pork on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/pork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cranberry Pork Chop Broil</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/cranberry-pork-chop-broil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/cranberry-pork-chop-broil/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>6 pork loin or rib chops, about 3/4 inch thick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 (8 oz.) can jellied cranberry sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp. lemon juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp. almond extract&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp. ground nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 (29 oz.) can peach halves, drained&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Set oven control to broil and/or 550 degrees. Broil pork chops with tops 3-5 inches from heat 5 minutes. Sprinkle with salt. Turn, broil 5 minutes longer. Sprinkle with salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat cranberry sauce, lemon juice, almond extract and nutmeg over low heat. Brush pork with sauce. Continue broiling, turning and brushing with sauce, until done, 10-15 minutes longer. Remove pork chops to platter; brush with sauce. Fill each peach half with about 1 teaspoon sauce; serve with pork.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pork and Ginger Pot Stickers</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-ginger-pot-stickers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-ginger-pot-stickers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="pork-and-ginger-filling">Pork and Ginger Filling&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 cups chopped napa cabbage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tablespoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 pound ground pork (Don&amp;rsquo;t get lean pork, the fat is good for juicy and flavorful dumplings)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons minced ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 tablespoons minced garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons thin soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons sesame oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 to 2 cups chicken stock or water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="hot-water-dough">Hot Water Dough&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 to 1 3/4 cups boiling water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="spicy-soy-dipping-sauce">Spicy Soy Dipping Sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/3 cup thin soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup rice wine vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup sliced scallions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon sesame oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon sambal&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Sprinkle cabbage with the 1/2 tablespoon of salt and let stand for 30 minutes. Place the cabbage on a clean dishtowel or cheesecloth and squeeze out any water. The dryer the cabbage the better. In a large bowl thoroughly mix the cabbage with all of the other ingredients, except the chicken stock. Cook a tester to check the seasoning.;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="hot-water-dough-1">Hot Water Dough&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a stainless steel bowl mix flour and salt. Slowly add hot water to flour in 1/4 cup increments. Mix with chopsticks until a ball is formed and the dough is not too hot to handle. On a floured surface, knead dough until it becomes a smooth, elastic ball. Place back in bowl and cover with a damp cloth. Allow to rest for at least 1 hour. Working on a floured surface with floured hands, roll out dough to form a long &amp;rsquo;noodle&amp;rsquo;, 1-inch in diameter. Cut 1/2-inch pieces and turn them over so the cut sides are facing up. Flatten with your palm and roll out thin using a rolling pin. The dumpling wrapper should end up about 3 inches in diameter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="making-the-dumplings">MAKING THE DUMPLINGS:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place a small mound of filling in the middle of the wrapper. (Be very careful not to touch the edges with the filling as this will impede proper sealing of the dumplings. Nothing is worse than dumplings breaking during cooking.) Fold the wrapper in half to form a half moon shape. Starting on one end fold/pinch the wrapper tightly together. Proceed with this fold/pinch method until the dumpling is completely sealed. There will be approximately 10 to 14 folds per dumpling. Rest the dumplings with the folded edges straight up.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="cooking-the-dumplings">COOKING THE DUMPLINGS&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a hot saute pan coated well with oil, place pot stickers flat side down and cook until the bottom is browned. Have pan cover ready and add 1 cup of chicken stock, cover immediately. Be careful, the liquid will splatter! The stock will steam the pot stickers. Check them in 5 minutes as more stock may be needed. The trick here is that once the dumplings are firm and fully cooked the stock will evaporate and the bottoms will crisp-up again.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="spicy-soy-dipping-sauce-1">SPICY SOY DIPPING SAUCE:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine all and serve in a small bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="plating">Plating&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Serve pot stickers on a large platter lined with lettuce with a bowl of dipping sauce on the side.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pork and Tomatillo Chili</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-tomatillo-chili/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-and-tomatillo-chili/</guid><description>&lt;p>This recipe from a story on chili-style dishes from around the world is one of those things that people just can’t stop eating; friends have been known to have thirds and then smile with slight embarrassment and serve themselves some more. Part of its appeal is that it smells so good while it’s cooking &amp;ndash; the combination of garlic, pork, orange juice and dark beer is extremely potent. It’s good served over rice or in bowls with corn bread on the side.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pork Enchiladas Suizo</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-enchiladas-suizo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/pork-enchiladas-suizo/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Slow Cooker Honey Lime Ginger Pork</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/slow-cooker-honey-lime-ginger-pork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/slow-cooker-honey-lime-ginger-pork/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2.5 pounds pork loin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tablespoon Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Honey Lime Ginger Marinade:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tablespoon Worcestershire Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Juice of one lime&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 garlic cloves minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon ground ginger or 1 Tablespoon fresh ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tablespoons cornstarch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optional garnish: Fresh lime wedges chopped cilantro&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a large skillet heat the oil over medium high heat. Salt and pepper the pork and lay in in the hot oil. Let the pork sear until the outside edge starts to blacken. Place the pork into the bottom of a slow cooker.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a small bowl whisk together the honey, soy sauce, Worcestershire sauce, juice of one lime, garlic cloves, and ginger. Pour the marinade over the pork. Let cook 6-8 hours on low and 4-6 hours on high or until thermometer reads 160 degrees.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the pork is finished lay onto a platter and pour the juices in a medium saucepan. Cook the marinade over medium high heat and whisk in the cornstarch. Cook for a few minutes until it starts to thicken. Pour over the pork. Garnish with optional lime wedges and fresh chopped cilantro.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>