<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chicken on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/chicken/</link><description>Recent content in Chicken on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/chicken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Balsamic chicken with figs and onion</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/balsamic-chicken-with-figs-and-onion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/balsamic-chicken-with-figs-and-onion/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>1 tbsp olive oil
1/2 tsp salt
1/2 tsp pepper
6 Chicken Thighs, Bone In Skin on
2 tbsp balsamic vinegar
1/2 tbsp dijon mustard
1 tbsp honey
*omit for Whole30
3 shallots
finely diced
2 cloves garlic
crushed
2 medium red onions
thinly sliced
1 tsp fresh thyme
1 cup chicken stock
2 cup shredded curly kale
5 figs
cut into halves/quarters depending on size&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chicken and Roasted Figs</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-and-roasted-figs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-and-roasted-figs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons good-quality (cask-aged) red wine vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon cornstarch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 pounds (4 to 6) bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon kosher salt, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 teaspoon pepper, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 large shallots, thinly sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 garlic cloves, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons chopped fresh oregano leaves, plus 2 tbsp. whole leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 to 10 figs, stems trimmed, halved (quartered if large)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 400°. In a small bowl, whisk together 1/4 cup water, the vinegar, and cornstarch. Whisk in honey and set aside. Sprinkle chicken on both sides with 3/4 tsp. salt and 1/2 tsp. pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a heavy 12- to 14-in. ovenproof frying pan over medium-high heat until hot. Add oil and swirl to coat, then add chicken skin side down and brown until skin is deep golden and crisp, 8 to 10 minutes. Turn over and brown other side, 2 to 3 minutes more. Transfer chicken to a plate and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discard all but 2 tbsp. fat from frying pan, reduce heat to medium, and cook shallots until translucent, 3 to 5 minutes. Add garlic and cook 1 minute more. Add cornstarch mixture, chopped oregano, and remaining 1/4 tsp. each salt and pepper; cook until mixture bubbles and thickens, 1 to 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set chicken skin side up in frying pan and add figs. Roast in oven until figs soften and caramelize slightly and meat is no longer pink at bone, about 15 minutes. Divide chicken, figs, and sauce among plates and top with whole oregano leaves.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Chicken Satay with Spicy Peanut Sauce</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-satay-with-spicy-peanut-sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-satay-with-spicy-peanut-sauce/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is an easy recipe for Chicken Tikka Masala&amp;ndash;chicken marinated in yogurt and spices and then served in a tomato cream sauce. Serve with rice or warm pita bread.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cranberry Balsamic Chicken</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/cranberry-balsamic-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/cranberry-balsamic-chicken/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Crock Pot Chicken</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/crock-pot-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/crock-pot-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1.5 teaspoons salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon cayenne pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon onion powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon white pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1⁄2 teaspoon garlic powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1⁄2 teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large roasting chicken (with pop-up timer if possible)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup chopped onion (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a small bowl, combine the spices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove any giblets from chicken and clean chicken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rub spice mixture onto the chicken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place in resealable plastic bag and refrigerate overnight. (I usually skip this step because I&amp;rsquo;m always in a hurry).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When ready to cook, put chopped onion in bottom of crock pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add chicken. No liquid is needed, the chicken will make its own juices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook on low 4-8 hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note: I highly recommend a pop-up timer in the chicken because some crock pots cook faster/slower than others (my crock pot cooks this recipe in 4-5 hours).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Funky Chicken</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/funky-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/funky-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="sesame-noodles">Sesame Noodles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>1 lb spaghettini (get the thinnest spaghetti you can find)
1⁄2 cup soy sauce
1⁄4 cup sesame oil (some reviewers have said that 1/2 cup of oil is too much and have halved the amount, so use your own)
1⁄3 cup sugar
3 scallions, thinly sliced
1⁄4 cup sesame seeds (or more)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Garlicky Chicken Thighs With Scallion and Lime</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/garlicky-chicken-thighs-with-scallion-and-lime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/garlicky-chicken-thighs-with-scallion-and-lime/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 ½ pounds bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kosher salt and freshly ground pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon canola oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bunch scallions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 head garlic, unpeeled and halved crosswise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves garlic, peeled and finely grated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons fresh lime juice, plus 1 lime&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon low-sodium soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Season chicken with salt and pepper on both sides.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat oil in a large Dutch oven or large, high-sided skillet over medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add chicken, skin-side down and cook, undisturbed, until chicken is crisped and the fat has begun to render, 8 to 10 minutes. Using tongs, carefully flip chicken skin-side up. Cook until golden brown, 4 to 6 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, thinly slice two scallions; set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add both halves of the head of garlic, cut side down, and remaining whole scallions to the pot and season with salt and pepper, tossing to coat in the chicken fat. Cook until scallions are lightly blistered and browned, about 3 minutes. Add grated garlic and stir a minute or two, but do not brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add lime juice, soy sauce and 1 cup of water. Bring to a simmer and partly cover. Cook until chicken is completely tender and nearly falling apart on the underside and liquid is reduced by three-quarters, 15 to 20 minutes. Discard the halved head of garlic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scatter sliced scallion over chicken and using a Microplane or zester, zest lime over. Cut lime into quarters and serve alongside.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>One Pot Chicken and Dirty Rice</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-and-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/one-pot-chicken-and-rice/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cups uncooked basmati rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 chicken thighs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 teaspoon mixed herbs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoon smoked paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon onion powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon garlic powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoon Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup onion chopped any types of onion would work for this recipe.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cups low sodium chicken stock.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and pepper to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup green onions to garnish sub with chives, parsley or coriander&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>To a small mixing bowl, add smoked paprika, mixed herbs, garlic powder, onion powder, salt and black pepper and mix to combine. Rinse the rice until the water runs clear and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mixed spices in a small glass bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the chicken thighs to a bigger bowl and add the seasoning reserving about a teaspoon for later. Mix until the chicken is well coated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>raw chicken coated with seasoning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat up olive oil on medium high heat, carefully add the chicken, skin side down and sear for about 3 minutes on each side until golden brown. Remove the chicken and place on a plate and set aside. (You can blot the oil with kitchen towel if it looks too much at this point as the chicken releases its own oil too)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>chicken searing in a skillet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sauté the chopped onions in the hot oil until soft and translucent, add the butter, and stir until melted. stir in the rinsed rice and toast for about a minute or two making sure it doesn’t stick to the bottom of the pan. Pour the chicken stock over the rice, add the reserved seasoning, and stir to combine. Deglaze the bottom of the pan while stirring by scraping the bottom of the pan. This way the rice doesn’t burn when cooking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Taste and adjust seasoning to taste at this point&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arrange the chicken thighs over the rice then cover the pot with its lid and cook on low-medium heat for about 15 to 20 minutes depending on the type of rice you are using. When the rice is done, it would be tender, fluffy and the water would be absorbed too.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>chicken in a pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garnish the rice with chopped green onions, cover and let it stand for another 3 minutes. fluff the rice with a fork, serve and enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>One-Pan Spanish Chicken and Rice</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/one-pan-spanish-chicken-and-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/one-pan-spanish-chicken-and-rice/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sheet-Pan Chicken With Chickpeas, Cumin and Turmeric</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/sheet-pan-chicken-with-chickpeas-cumin-and-turmeric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/sheet-pan-chicken-with-chickpeas-cumin-and-turmeric/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 (3 1/2 to 4 pound) chicken, cut into parts (alternatively, 3 to 3 1/2 pounds of bone-in, skin-on chicken parts, such as breasts, thighs and legs)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kosher salt and freshly ground pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ cups full-fat Greek yogurt, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 tablespoons fresh lemon juice, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons ground turmeric, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 (15-ounce) cans chickpeas, drained and rinsed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon fennel seed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon ground cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large red onion, thinly sliced, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ cup mint or cilantro leaves, torn&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Season chicken parts with salt and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine 3/4 cup yogurt, 2 tablespoons lemon juice, 1 teaspoon turmeric and 2 tablespoons water in a large bowl. Season well with salt and pepper. (It should be on the salty side, as this is a marinade.) Add chicken and toss to coat evenly. Let sit at least 30 minutes at room temperature, and up to overnight in the refrigerator.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place oven rack on the top third of the oven and heat to 425 degrees.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine chickpeas, fennel seed, cumin, remaining teaspoon of turmeric and half the red onion slices on a rimmed baking sheet. Drizzle with olive oil, season with salt and pepper and toss to coat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move chickpeas to the outer edges of the baking sheet. Scrape any excess marinade off the chicken, and place the chicken parts in the center. Place baking sheet in oven and bake, tossing chickpeas occasionally, until the skin of the chicken is evenly browned and the chickpeas are golden and starting to crisp, 45 to 50 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, toss remaining onion slices with 2 tablespoons lemon juice and season with salt and pepper; set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine remaining yogurt with remaining 1 tablespoon lemon juice and season with salt and pepper; set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once chicken is ready, scatter with lemony onions and mint or cilantro. Serve with seasoned yogurt alongside as a sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Skillet Chicken</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/skillet-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/skillet-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 lemons, juiced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>⅓ cup olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 garlic cloves, peeled and smashed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ teaspoon kosher salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons ground cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons ground paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ teaspoon ground turmeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ pounds bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs (about 4)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 yellow onion, peeled and chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ cups long-grain white or sprouted short-grain brown rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 ¾ cups boiling water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cinnamon stick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ cup raisins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ cup chopped fresh mint, for serving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons chopped fresh parsley, for serving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plain yogurt, for serving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lime wedges, for serving&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine the lemon juice, 1/4 cup of the olive oil, the garlic, 1 teaspoon salt, pepper, cumin, paprika and turmeric in a large resealable plastic bag along with the chicken pieces. Seal and shake the bag to coat chicken and distribute the spices evenly. Set aside for 30 minutes, or refrigerate up to overnight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat the remaining tablespoon of olive oil in a large cast-iron skillet over medium-high heat. Remove the chicken from the marinade, letting the excess drip off, and cook until lightly golden, about 4 minutes per side. Remove to a plate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the onion to the pan, and stir to coat. Decrease heat to medium and cook until softening, about 5 minutes. Add the rice and remaining salt, and stir to coat. Add the boiling water; stir, cover and cook until the liquid is partly absorbed, 10 minutes. Stir in the cinnamon stick and raisins, top with the chicken thighs and their juices, and continue cooking, covered, over medium heat, until the rice is al dente and the chicken is completely tender, about 25 minutes more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove from the heat and scatter the mint and parsley all over the top. Serve warm, with yogurt and lime.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="tip">Tip&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Some cast-iron skillets come with a matching lid, which is useful for making the skillet operate a bit like a mini stove-top oven, cooking evenly and basting the food with flavor and steam. If you don’t have one, use a lid from another pan, or two layers of thick foil, folded at the center and large enough to cover your pan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skillet Honey Garlic Chicken Thighs With Roast Potatoes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/skillet-honey-garlic-chicken-thighs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/skillet-honey-garlic-chicken-thighs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Juicy honey garlic chicken thighs and crispy roast potatoes are seared and baked in the most FLAVORFUL honey garlic sauce in this no-fuss one skillet dinner!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Slow Cooker Chickpea Pumpkin Curry</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/slow-cooker-chickpea-pumpkin-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/slow-cooker-chickpea-pumpkin-curry/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ultimate Chicken Pot Pie</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/ultimate-chicken-pot-pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/ultimate-chicken-pot-pie/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>