<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Canning-and-Pickling on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/canning-and-pickling/</link><description>Recent content in Canning-and-Pickling on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/canning-and-pickling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Barrel Fermented Pickles</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/barrel-fermented-pickles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/barrel-fermented-pickles/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pickling cucumbers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sea salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fresh dill&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peppercorns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grape leaves (these keep the pickles crisp)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fermentation barrel or crock&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Pick through the cucumbers and remove any that are moldy, squishy, or damaged. Only the best can make it into the crock, man. You can gently rinse them in water, if you need to remove dirt or debris.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill the crock half full of cucumbers before laying in a few sprigs of fresh dill, a clove of garlic, a chunk of onion, a pinch of peppercorns, and a few grape leaves. Stop it. I can hear you complaining. Yes, I realize this is vague – but that’s okay. They’re your pickles and you can spice them with whatever you like! I haven’t noticed a bit enough difference between using different measurements of spices to waste the time being precise about it all.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill a quart jar with filtered water and 1 1/2 tablespoons sea salt. Stir to dissolve the salt and pour this over the cucumbers. Continue to fill the quart jar with this same water and salt mixture, pouring it over the cucumbers each time, until the crock is full and the cucumbers can be completely submerged in the liquid.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place a crock weight (or plate if you don’t have one) over the top of the pickles so that they remain completely submerged during the course of their fermentation. You can also layer on some grape leaves to help protect the cucumbers from oxygen as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Fig Preserves</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/fig-preserves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/fig-preserves/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons baking soda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 cups fresh figs, stems removed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ cups white sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 tablespoons butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 lemon, thinly sliced into rounds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon lemon juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ teaspoons ground cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon grated fresh ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ teaspoon ground cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 pinch salt, or to taste (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 half-pint canning jars with lids and rings&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Dissolve the baking soda in about 2 quarts of cool water, and immerse the figs in the treated water in a large bowl. Gently stir to wash the figs, then drain off the water and rinse the figs thoroughly with fresh cool water. Place the figs into a large pot. Add 1 cup water, sugar, butter, vanilla extract, lemon, lemon juice, cinnamon, ginger, and cloves. Very gently stir the mixture to dissolve the sugar, keeping the figs intact as much as possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring the mixture to a boil over medium heat; reduce heat to a simmer, and cook until the figs are golden brown and coated in syrup, about 1 hour. Stir gently a couple of times to keep the figs from burning onto the bottom of the pot. Add a pinch of salt, if desired, to tame the sweetness.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sterilize the jars and lids in boiling water for at least 5 minutes. Pack the figs into the hot, sterilized jars and top off with syrup, filling the jars to within 1/4 inch of the top. Run a knife or a thin spatula around the insides of the jars after they have been filled to remove any air bubbles. Wipe the rims of the jars with a moist paper towel to remove any food residue. Top with lids, and screw on rings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place a rack in the bottom of a large stockpot and fill halfway with water. Bring to a boil over high heat, then carefully lower the jars into the pot using a holder. Leave a 2 inch space between the jars. Pour in more boiling water if necessary until the water level is at least 1 inch above the tops of the jars. Bring the water to a full boil, cover the pot, and process for 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the jars from the stockpot and place onto a cloth-covered or wood surface, several inches apart, until cool. Once cool, press the top of each lid with a finger, ensuring that the seal is tight (lid does not move up or down at all). Store in a cool, dark area, and wait at least 2 days before opening.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the whole figs in the pot, and let them break apart naturally, do not cut them in half.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you do not seal jars in boiling water, the mixture must be eaten in 30 days.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Saurkraut</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/saurkraut/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/saurkraut/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>5 pounds green cabbage, shredded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons pickling salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon juniper berries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons caraway seeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 quart water, in a sanitized glass jar&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In large mixing bowl, mix cabbage thoroughly with salt, juniper berries, and caraway seeds, using hands or tongs. If using your hands, make sure that they are very clean prior to mixing. Let stand for 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pack cabbage mixture down into a large plastic food container. Top with a lid smaller than the opening of the container and place a glass jar filled with the quart of water on top of the lid. Place in cool area overnight (65 to 70 degrees F). In a day, the cabbage should have given up enough liquid to be completely submerged. The jar serves as a weight to keep the cabbage submerged and away from air.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check cabbage every other day for approximately 2 weeks and skim the surface of scum, if necessary. Let stand for 4 weeks. Transfer to an airtight container and store in the refrigerator for up to 6 months.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Squash Pickles</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/squash-pickles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/squash-pickles/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>¼ cup salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 ½ pounds young yellow squash and zucchini, sliced into rounds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 green bell pepper, seeded and sliced into strips&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 small onions, thinly sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 ¼ cups white sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cups distilled white vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons mustard seed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon ground turmeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon celery seed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In a large non-aluminum pot, combine the squash, bell pepper, and onions. Cover with salt, and let stand for 2 hours to release the liquids. Stir occasionally.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sweet Zucchini Relish</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/zucchini-relish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/zucchini-relish/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="saras-modifications">Sara&amp;rsquo;s Modifications:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>only use 1 cup sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>double all spices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>omit nutmeg, cornstarch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="original-ingredients">Original Ingredients&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>12 cups shredded unpeeled zucchini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cups chopped onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 tablespoons canning salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 red bell pepper, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 green bell pepper, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 cups white sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 ½ cups white vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon cornstarch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¾ teaspoon ground nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¾ teaspoon ground turmeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ teaspoons celery seed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ teaspoon ground black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place the zucchini and onion in a large, non-metallic bowl, and sprinkle the salt overtop. Use your hands to evenly mix the salt throughout the zucchini. Cover, and refrigerate overnight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The following day, drain the zucchini in a colander, and rinse well with cool water. Squeeze out excess water and set aside. Place the red and green bell pepper, sugar, vinegar, and cornstarch into a large pot. Add the nutmeg, turmeric, celery seed and pepper. Stir to combine, then add the drained zucchini. Bring to a boil over medium-high heat, then reduce the heat to medium-low, and simmer 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, sterilize 7 one-pint jars and lids to hold relish. Pack relish into sterilized jars, making sure there are no spaces or air pockets. Fill jars all the way to top. Screw on lids.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place a rack in the bottom of a large stockpot and fill halfway with boiling water. Carefully lower jars into pot using a holder. Leave a 2 inch space between jars. Pour in more boiling water if necessary, until tops of jars are covered by 2 inches of water. Bring water to a full boil, then cover and process for 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove jars from pot and place on cloth-covered or wood surface, several inches apart, until cool. Once cool, press top of each lid with finger, ensuring that seal is tight (lid does not move up or down at all).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>