<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Canning-and-Pickling on Dan Aukes</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/canning-and-pickling/</link><description>Recent content in Canning-and-Pickling on Dan Aukes</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.danaukes.com/recipe_tags/canning-and-pickling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Barrel Fermented Pickles</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/barrel-fermented-pickles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/barrel-fermented-pickles/</guid><description>Ingredients Pickling cucumbers Sea salt Water Fresh dill Garlic cloves Onion Peppercorns Grape leaves (these keep the pickles crisp) Fermentation barrel or crock Directions Pick through the cucumbers and remove any that are moldy, squishy, or damaged.</description></item><item><title>Fig Preserves</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/fig-preserves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/fig-preserves/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 teaspoons baking soda 5 cups fresh figs, stems removed 1 cup water 1 ½ cups white sugar 5 tablespoons butter 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 1 lemon, thinly sliced into rounds 1 tablespoon lemon juice 1 ½ teaspoons ground cinnamon 1 teaspoon grated fresh ginger ½ teaspoon ground cloves 1 pinch salt, or to taste (optional) 8 half-pint canning jars with lids and rings Directions Dissolve the baking soda in about 2 quarts of cool water, and immerse the figs in the treated water in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Saurkraut</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/saurkraut/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/saurkraut/</guid><description>Ingredients 5 pounds green cabbage, shredded 3 tablespoons pickling salt 1 tablespoon juniper berries 2 teaspoons caraway seeds 1 quart water, in a sanitized glass jar Directions In large mixing bowl, mix cabbage thoroughly with salt, juniper berries, and caraway seeds, using hands or tongs.</description></item><item><title>Squash Pickles</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/squash-pickles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/squash-pickles/</guid><description>Ingredients ¼ cup salt 2 ½ pounds young yellow squash and zucchini, sliced into rounds 1 green bell pepper, seeded and sliced into strips 2 small onions, thinly sliced 2 ¼ cups white sugar 2 cups distilled white vinegar 2 teaspoons mustard seed 1 teaspoon ground turmeric 1 teaspoon celery seed Directions In a large non-aluminum pot, combine the squash, bell pepper, and onions.</description></item><item><title>Sweet Zucchini Relish</title><link>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/zucchini-relish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.danaukes.com/recipes/zucchini-relish/</guid><description>Ingredients Sara&amp;rsquo;s Modifications: only use 1 cup sugar double all spices omit nutmeg, cornstarch Original Ingredients 12 cups shredded unpeeled zucchini 4 cups chopped onion 5 tablespoons canning salt 1 red bell pepper, chopped 1 green bell pepper, chopped 6 cups white sugar 2 ½ cups white vinegar 1 tablespoon cornstarch ¾ teaspoon ground nutmeg ¾ teaspoon ground turmeric 1 ½ teaspoons celery seed ½ teaspoon ground black pepper Steps Place the zucchini and onion in a large, non-metallic bowl, and sprinkle the salt overtop.</description></item></channel></rss>